Guide to the George Eliot and George Henry Lewes Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section III. Letters to/about GEORGE ELIOT & GEORGE HENRY LEWES
  - Lewes, Charles Lee, 1842-1891
    - to GHL, 1857 Mar 29
      - ----, 1859 Feb 13 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1859 Apr 17 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1859 May 15 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1859 Jul 3 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1859 Aug 18 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1871 Aug 9 (Box 10)
    - to GE and GHL, [1859] Oct 16
      - ----, 1860 Jan 1 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1860 Jan 15 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1861 Feb 4 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1861 Apr 25 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1861 May 11 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1864 May 13 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1864 May 23 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1864 May 31 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1865 Apr 13 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1866 Sep 24 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1868 Jul 25 (Box 10)
      - ----, 1871 May 21 (Box 10)
    - to Edward Pigott, 1878 Dec 9 (Box 10)
  - Lewes, Edgar James, d.?1836
    - to his mother, Elizabeth (Ashweek) Lewes Willim (Mrs. John Willim, 1787-1870), 1825 May 27 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1825 Aug 2 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1825 Nov 4 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1836 [i.e. 1826] (Box 10)
    - ---- ----, 1826 Aug 29 (Box 10)
    - I write this upon getting..., 1827 Mar 16 (Box 10)
    - I write this immediately..., 1827 Mar 16 (Box 10)
    - I am arrived safe..., 1827 Mar 16 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1827 Mar 20 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1828 Jan 22 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1828 Aug 4 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1828 Sep 23 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1829 Jan 20 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1830 Feb 10 (Box 10)
      In a wrapper with genealogy of Elinor Southwood Lewes Ouvry on front cover. [to Edward and George Henry Lewes] A true, literal & exact account of the Goods, Chattels & other appurtenances of Edgar James Lewes. 10 quatrains of comic verse, signed. 2 p.
    - to Charles Seaforth, 1825 Jun 11 (Box 10)
  - Lewes, Gertrude (Hill); (Mrs. Charles Lee Lewes), 1837-1923
    - to J.W. Cross with MS map of Chelsea, [1881] (Box 10)
    - ----, 1882 Jul 14 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1902 Jul 23 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1919 Mar 11 (Box 10)
    - ----, 1919 Apr 2 (Box 10)
      Envelope in the hand of Mrs. C.L. Lewes, with note about the cast of GE's head, August 1890.
  - Lewes, Herbert Arthur, 1846-1875
    - to GE, 1859 Aug 26 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Sep (Box 11)
    - to GE and GHL, 1859 Oct
      - ----, 1866 Sep 16 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1867 Oct 27 (Box 11)
    - to Agnes Lewes, 1858 Nov 9 (Box 11)
    - to GHL, [1855?]
      - ----, 1859 Aug [24] (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Jul 27 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1861] Jan 13 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Feb 3 (Box 11)
      - I don't know..., 1861 (Box 11)
      - I am much obliged..., 1861 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1866 Nov 5 (Box 11)
      - Report card at Hofwyl School, 1860 (Box 11)
  - Lewes, Thornton Arnott, 1844-1869
    - to GHL, GE, or both, 1855 Dec 6
      - ----, 1857 Mar 1 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1857 May 21 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1857 Oct 2 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1857 Dec 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Jan 31 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Apr 8 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 May 2 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 May 23 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 May 30 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Aug 19-21 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Nov 7 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Nov 28 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Jan 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Mar 28 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Jun 5 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Jun 15 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Aug 18 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Sep 9 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Nov 17 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 [i.e. 1860] (Box 11)
      - ---- ----, 1860 Feb 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Mar 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 May 16 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Sep 11 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Oct 2 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Oct 13 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Nov 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1860 Dec 11] (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 [i.e. 1861] (Box 11)
      - ---- ----, 1861 Jan 14 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Jan 27 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Feb 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Feb 17 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Mar 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Apr 14 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Apr 17 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 May 7 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Jun 25 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Oct 20 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Nov 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1861 Dec 22 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1862 Jan 19 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1863 Nov 14 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1863 Dec 30 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1864 Jan 28 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1864 Aug 29 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1864 Oct 7 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1865 Jun 12- (Box 11)
      - ---- ----, 1865 Sep 22 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1865 Dec 26 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1866 Feb 24 (Box 11)
      - The beginning..., 1866 Jun 2 (Box 11)
      - Having just returned..., 1866 Jun 2 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1866 Oct 9 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1866 Dec 9 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1867 Apr 10 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1867 Jun 16 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1867 Jul 12 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1867 Sep 16 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1868 Mar 9- (Box 11)
      - ---- ----, 1868 Oct 12 (Box 11)
    - Juvenilia., 1855-[1860]
      - Stories - The Magic Wand & The Knight of the Crescent. 32 p., 1855 Jul (Box 11)
      - Diary, [1855] Aug 9-15 (Box 11)
      - Ramsgate. 2 p., [1855] (Box 11)
      - Fragments of Poems - 17 pieces, [1856-1860?] (Box 11)
    - School reports
      - Bayswater School by T.A.L., 1856 Jul 9 (Box 11)
      - Hofwyl School, 1857 Dec 24 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Mar 31 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Jul 30 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1858 Dec 23 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Apr 21 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1859 Jul 28 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1860 Apr 5 (Box 11)
  - Lewis, Elisabeth (Eberstadt) Mrs. George Henry (later Lady) Lewis
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 5 (Box 11)
  - Lewis, Maria, 1800?-1887
    - to GE, 1874 Sep 22
      - ----, 1875 Jun 22 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1879 Jan 22 (Box 11)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1881 Jul 19
      - ----, 1885 Jan 14 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1885 Mar?] (Box 11)
      - Tinker 995 (Box 11)
  - Leys, J.K.
    - to GE, 1875 Jul (Box 11)
  - Leys, Mary
    - to GE, 1875 Aug 9 (Box 11)
  - Lindsay, Caroline Blanche Elizabeth (Fitz Roy), Lady
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 4 (Box 11)
  - Lowell, James Russell
    - to GE, 1880 Aug 27 (Box 11)
  - Lowndes, Marie Adelaide (Belloc), 1868-1947
    - to Elsie Druce, 1942 Apr 15 (Box 11)
    - ----, 1944 Jan 18 (Box 11)
    - ----, 1944 Jun 24 (Box 11)
      Correspondence with Gordon S. Haight from 1942-1947, and correspondence between Mr. Haight and Elizabeth, Countess of Iddesleigh (Mrs. Belloc Lowndes's daughter) from 1947-1957.
  - Lucas, Samuel, 1818-1868
    - to GE, 1859 Apr 5 (Box 11)
  - Ludden, Karl
    - to GE, 1870 Sep 18-20 (Box 11)
  - Lytton, Edith Villiers, Countess of
    - to GE, 1872 Dec 9 (Box 11)
  - Lytton, Edward George Earle Lytton Bulwer-Lytton, 1st baron, 1803-1873
    - to GHL, [1848 Mar 8] (Box 11)
    - ----, 1863 Oct 1 (Box 11)
  - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 1st earl of, 1831-1891
    - to GE, [1862 April] (Box 11)
    - to GHL, 1866 Feb 11
      - ----, 1866 Jun 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1868?] (Box 11)
      - Friday, [1871 Dec ?] (Box 11)
      - ----, [1872 n.d.] (Box 11)
      - ----, 1872 Mar 23 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1872 Apr 29 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1874 Apr 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1874] Jun 8 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 Feb 19 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 Feb 25 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 Mar 5 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 Mar 6 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1875 Mar 12] (Box 11)
      - ----, [1875 Mar 16] (Box 11)
      - ----, [1875 Apr 6] (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 Apr 16 (Box 11)
      - ----, [1875 May 1] (Box 11)
      - ----, 1875 May 6 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1876 Apr 24 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1877 Jan 23 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1877 Jun 3 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1877 Aug 18 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1877 Oct 28 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1878 Mar 23-26 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1878 Mar 26 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1878 May 8 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1878 May 23 (Box 11)
      - ----, 1878 Jul 27 (Box 11)
  - M'Cormack, Henry
    - to GE, 1860 Jun 1 (Box 12)
  - Macaulay, Thomas Babington Macaulay, 1st baron, 1800-1859
    - to GHL, 1845 Feb 4 (Box 12)
  - Macquoid, Katharine S. (Mrs. Thomas R. Macquoid)
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 12)
  - Magnus, Katie (Emanuel), Lady
    - to GE, 1879 Jun 19 (Box 12)
  - Main, Alexander, 1841-1918
    - to GE and GHL, 1873 Nov 24
      - ----, 1874 Jan 6 (Box 12)
    - to GHL, 1874 Feb 24 (Box 12)
  - Maine, Sir Henry James Sumner, 1822-1888
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 20 (Box 12)
  - Malleson, Elizabeth (Whitehead), (Mrs. Frank Rodbard Malleson), 1828-1916
    - to Barbara L.S. Bodichon, [1863] Aug 21 (Box 12)
  - Mario, Jessie Meriton (White), (Mrs. Alberto Mario), 1832-1906
    - to GE, 1878 Nov 3 (Box 12)
  - Martin, Helena Saville (Faucit), Lady, 1817-1898
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 11 (Box 12)
  - Martin, Sir Theodore, 1816-1909
    - to John Blackwood, 1859 Apr 3 (Box 12)
      Tinker 997
  - Martineau, Harriet, 1802-1876
    - to GHL, No year Dec 10 (Box 12)
  - Masson, David, 1822-1907
    - to Robert Vaughan, 1795-1868, 1852 May 8 (Box 12)
  - Mathers, Helen Buckingham (Box 12)
    See: Reeves, Helen Buckingham (Mathers)
  - Mathews, Charles James, 1803-1878
    - to GHL, 1853 Oct 9 (Box 12)
  - Maybury, Anna M.L.
    - to GE, 1875 Aug 26 (Box 12)
  - Méren, Marianne
    - to GE, [1872?] (Box 12)
  - Mill, John Stuart
    - Wednesday, [1841 Feb 24?] (Box 12)
    - ----, 1841 Mar 1 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1841 Apr 24
      - Saturday, [1841 Aug] (Box 12)
      - Wednesday, [1842 Dec 7] (Box 12)
      - Friday, [1843 Mar?] (Box 12)
      - Envelope addressed to GHL, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Montalba, Anthony
    - to GE, [1878 Dec?] (Box 12)
  - Montefiore, Leonard A.
    - Wednesday, [1877 Oct 17] (Box 12)
  - Montgomery, Mary Millicent
    - to GE, [1852 Nov 10] (Box 12)
  - Morley, John, 1838-1923
    - to J.W. Cross, 1885 Jan 13 (Box 12)
  - Mottram, William
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 9 (Box 12)
  - Moule, Horace Mosley
    - to GE, [1868] Sep 24 (Box 12)
  - Mount-Temple, Georgiana (Tollemache) Cowper-Temple, baroness, 1822-1901 (Box 12)
    See: Cowper-Temple, Georginia (Tollemache), Lady
  - Myers, Asher Isaac, 1848-1902
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 17 (Box 12)
  - Myers, Frederic William Henry, 1843-1901
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 28
      - ----, 1881 Feb 13 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1881 Mar 5 (Box 12)
      - Tinker 998 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1885 Feb 19 (Box 12)
    - to GE, 1872 Dec 8
      - ----, 1878 Dec 10 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1880 May 20 (Box 12)
      - Tinker 999 (Box 12)
    - to William Henry Hall, 1880 May 7 (Box 12)
    - to Charles Lee Lewes, 1881 Nov 30 (Box 12)
  - National Portrait Gallery (Box 12)
    See: Scharf, Sir George
  - Neubauer, Adolf, 1832-1907
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 8 (Box 12)
  - Nichols, T.L.
    - to GE, 1873 Apr 5 (Box 12)
  - Nicholson, Mrs. W. A.
    - to GE, 1859 May 2 (Box 12)
  - Norton, Susan (Sedgwick), (Mrs. Charles Eliot Norton)
    - to GE, [1869] Dec 7 (Box 12)
    - ----, [1869] Dec 18 (Box 12)
  - Nutt, David
    - Agreement. Signed by Nutt and GHL for publication of GHL's Goethe., 1855 Jun (Box 12)
  - Orr, Alexandra (Leighton), (Mrs. Sutherland Orr), 1828-1903
    - Monday, [1878 Dec 2?] (Box 12)
  - Otter, Emily Helen (Cross), 1848-1907
    to GE and GHL
    - Tuesday afternoon, [1875 Jan 12] (Box 12)
    - signed by Emily H. and Francis Otter, [1878] Dec 3 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1880 Apr 16 (Box 12)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 May 24
      - ----, [1880] Dec 27 (Box 12)
  - Otter, Francis, d. 1895
    - to J.W. Cross, 1882 Sep 11 (Box 12)
    - to GE, 1880 Apr 17 (Box 12)
  - Ouvry, Elinor Southwood (Lewes)
    - to Elsie Druce, 1925 [Feb?]
      Note on Arthur Paterson and his sister Helen (Paterson) Allingham.
      - Receipt for Romola photographs. £10 paid by the Royal Borough of Kensington to Ellis & Ellis, Mrs. Ouvry's solicitors., 1931 Feb 11 (Box 12)
  - Owen, Sir Richard, 1804-1892
    - to GHL, 1856 Jan 1 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1857 Jul 14 (Box 12)
  - Paget, Sir James, 1814-1899
    - to GE, 1872 Dec 7 (Box 12)
  - Papé, Charlotte
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 12)
  - Parrish, Morris L.
    - to Mrs. Elinor Ouvry, 1932 May 16 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1933 Jun 28 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1933 Jul 24 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1935 Feb 19 (Box 12)
    - from Mrs. Elinor Ouvry
      - Draft of a reply to Mr. Parrish's letter of 28 Jun 1933., n.d. (Box 12)
      - Copy of a letter from GE to Julia Margaret Cameron, 17 Jan 1871, with notes by Mrs. Ouvry, Feb 1942. (Box 12)
  - Paterson, Arthur
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1926 Apr 17 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1926 Jul 26 (Box 12)
  - Paterson, Mary M. (Mrs. Arthur Paterson)
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1928 Apr 6 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1928 May 5 (Box 12)
  - Patterson, Robert Hogarth, 1821-1886
    - to John Blackwood, [1868 Jun] (Box 12)
  - Paul, Charles Kegan, 1828-1902
    - to GE, 1880 May 8 (Box 12)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 12)
  - Peirce, Melusina (Fay) (Mrs. Charles Sanders Peirce), 1836-
    - to GE, 1869 Aug 2 (Box 12)
  - Pelly, Sir Lewis, 1825-1892
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 12)
  - Perry, Alice M.
    - to GE, 1880 Feb 6 (Box 12)
  - Pfeiffer, Emily (Davis), 1827-1890
    - to GE, No year Nov 17 (Box 12)
    - ----, [1879] Jan 11 (Box 12)
  - Pigott, Edward Frederick Smyth, 1824-1895
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 May 7 (Box 12)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 12)
  - Ponsonby, Mary Elizabeth (Bulteel), Lady, 1832-1916
    - to GE, 1874 Oct
      - ----, 1874 Dec 4 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1875 Feb 6 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1875 Feb 9 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1875 Feb 14 (Box 12)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 12)
  - Poole, Hester M.
    - to GE, [1868] Sep 3 (Box 12)
  - Portsmouth, Eveline Alicia Juliana (Herbert), Countess of, 1834-1906
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 8 (Box 12)
  - Quirk, James R.
    - to GE, 1859 Aug 18 (Box 12)
  - Quirk, Ralph
    - San Mateo, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Quain, Richard, 1800-1887
    - to Sir James Paget, [1879] Apr 22 (Box 12)
  - Ramsay, Edward Bannerman, 1793-1872
    - to GE, 1866 Aug 9 (Box 12)
  - Read, John Edmund
    - to GE, [1859] May 12 (Box 12)
  - Reeves, Helen Buckingham (Mathers), 1853-1920
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880 Dec 22] (Box 12)
  - Ritchie, Anne Isabella (Thackeray) Lady, 1837-1919
    - to J.W. Cross, [1880 Dec] (Box 12)
      Tinker 1000
    - to C.L. Lewes, n.y. Jun 2 (Box 12)
    - to G.H. Lewes
      - Saturday, [1870?] (Box 12)
      - Friday, [1872 Jan] (Box 12)
  - Ritter, Charles
    - to GE, 1872 Jun 20
      - ----, 1873 Feb 7 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1873 Apr 26 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1874 Dec 29 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1875 Oct 22 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1877 May 25 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1877 Jul 15 (Box 12)
      - ----, 1877 Oct 10 (Box 12)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1881 Mar 28
      - ----, 1887 Apr 9 (Box 12)
  - Rolleston, George, 1829-1881
    - to GHL, [1877] May 19 (Box 12)
  - Ruck, Mary Anne (Mrs. Lawrence Ruck)
    - to GE, [1867?] Mar 3 (Box 12)
    - ----, 1873 May 1 (Box 12)
    - You are no new friend..., [1876] (Box 12)
    - I think it very good of you..., [1876] (Box 12)
    - ----, [1878] Dec 10 (Box 12)
  - Rudge, Mrs. E.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 3 (Box 12)
  - Ruge, H. Arnold, 1803-1880
    - to GHL, [1861?] (Box 12)
  - Russell, Lord Arthur John Edward
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 4 (Box 12)
  - Sadler, Thomas
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 23 (Box 12)
  - Sampson, George, 1873-1950
    - to Elinor Ouvry, 1928 May 18 (Box 12)
  - Sandars, Thomas Collett, 1825-1894
    - to J.W. Cross, 1885 Feb 8 (Box 13)
  - Sartoris, Adelaide (Kemble), (Mrs. Edward John Sartoris), 1814?-1879
    - to GE, 1873 Apr 7 (Box 13)
  - Scharf, Sir George, 1820-1895
    to C.L. Lewes
    - Accepting Burton's portrait of, 1883 Feb 23 (Box 13)
    - GE for National Portrait Gallery. Engraved form accepting "three, 1883 May 5 (Box 13)
    - specimens of the original hand- writing" of GE. (Box 13)
  - Schöll, Gustav Adolf
    - to GHL, 1854 Aug 8 (Box 13)
  - Scooner, William Baptiste
    - to GE, 1879 Sep 16 (Box 13)
  - Sellar, Alexander Craig
    - to J.W. Cross, 1882 Aug 31 (Box 13)
  - Sellar, Eleanor (Dennistoun), d. 1918
    - to J.W. Cross, [1878] Dec 28 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1880] Dec 28 (Box 13)
  - Sellar, William Young, 1825-1890
    - to J.W. Cross, 1881 Jan 2 (Box 13)
  - Senior, Jane Elizabeth (Hughes), (Mrs. Nassau John Senior), 1828-1877
    - to GE, 1876 Jun 30
      - with quotation from G.E. Maurice, 1876 Nov 29 (Box 13)
  - Shackleton, Lydia
    - to GHL, 1858 May 24 (Box 13)
  - Sharpe, John
    to J.W. Parker & Son
    - Asking about GHL's Biographical History of Philosophy, 1857 Nov 15 (Box 13)
  - Shorter, Clement K.
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 31 (Box 13)
  - Sidgwick, Eleanor Mildred (Balfour), (Mrs. Henry Sidgwick)
    - to GE, 1880 Apr 29
      - ----, [1880] Nov 4 (Box 13)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1901 Jun 6 (Box 13)
  - Sidgwick, Henry, 1838-1900
    - Many thanks for your criticisims..., n.d. (Box 13)
    - ----, [1880] Dec 25 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1881 Mar 27 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Nov 22 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Dec 15 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1885 Feb 11 (Box 13)
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 5
      - ----, [1880] Apr 29 (Box 13)
  - Siebold, Antonie von
    - to GE, [1858 Jun 18] (Box 13)
  - Siebold, Karl Theodor Ernst von, 1804-1885, and Antonie von Siebold
    - to GE, 1860 Apr 30- (Box 13)
    - ---- (Box 13)
  - Simcox, Edith, 1844-1901
    - to C.L. Lewes, [1878 Dec 2] (Box 13)
  - Simon, John, 1816-1904
    - Monday evening, [1859?] (Box 13)
  - Simon, Richard
    - Enclosing a poem entitled "New Lives", 1874 Aug 16 (Box 13)
  - Smart, Alice C., (Mrs. C.S. Smart)
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 30 (Box 13)
  - Smart, C.S.
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 31 (Box 13)
  - Smith, Anne Leigh
    - to GE, [1859 Jun] (Box 13)
    - Caricature of Joseph Liggins, [1859 Jul] (Box 13)
    - ----, [1859 Sep?] (Box 13)
    - ----, [1859 Nov] (Box 13)
  - Smith, Elder & Co.
    - Memorandum of agreement concerning the publication of GHL's Studies of Animal Life, [1859] (Box 13)
  - Smith, George, 1824-1901
    - to GE, 1864 May 3 (Box 13)
  - Smith, George Barnett, 1841-1909
    - to GE, 1872 Dec 6 (Box 13)
      Signed "Guy Roslyn."
      Tinker 1001
  - Smith, Lucy Caroline (Cumming), (Mrs. William Henry Smith)
    - to GE, [1873] Apr 24 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1873] Oct 23 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1874] Feb 14 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1874] Jun 27 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1878] Dec 3 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1879] Mar 28 (Box 13)
  - Smith, William Robertson, 1846-1894
    - with 12 pages of extracts on aphasia, etc., 1871 Sep 25 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1872 Dec 19 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1873 Apr 8 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1874 Jan 7 (Box 13)
  - Souvestre, Marie
    - to GE, [1873 Jun 29] (Box 13)
  - Spence, C.H.
    - to GE, 1876 Nov 23 (Box 13)
  - Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
    Tinker 1002
    - It occurred to me..., n.d. (Box 13)
    - ----, 1881 Mar 9 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1881 Mar 16 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1881 Apr 3 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1883 Dec 21 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Jan 13 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 21 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 23 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 24 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 27 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1884 Oct 29 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1885 Feb 2 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1885 Feb 9 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1885 Mar 14 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1889 Oct 13 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1892 Dec 7 (Box 13)
  - Steele, Joseph
    - to GE, 1855 Oct 7 (Box 13)
  - Stephen, Sir James FitzJames, 1829-1894
    - to GE, 1872 Nov 4 (Box 13)
  - Stewart, James S.
    - to Longman's Green, 1877 Aug 22 (Box 13)
  - Stoddard, Charles Warren
    - to GE, 1868 Sep 6 (Box 13)
      Accompanied by printed verses.
  - Stoddard, John L.
    - to GE, 1870 Nov 19 (Box 13)
  - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher), 1811-1896
    - to GE, [1878 Dec] (Box 13)
      (fragment)
  - Strachey, Jane Maria (Grant), Lady
    - to GE, [1879?] Apr 23 (Box 13)
  - Strangford, Emily Anne (Beaumont), Viscountess, d. 1887
    - to GE, 1873 Oct 27 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1874 Mar 6 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1874 Apr 23 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1874 May 30 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1879 Jan 9 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1880 May 8 (Box 13)
  - Streeter, Ada Louise, b. 1864?
    - to GE, 1880 Jan 12 (Box 13)
  - Stuart, Evorilda Eliza Maria (Fraser) (Mrs. John Glass Gordon Stuart), 1837?-1903
    - to GE, 1872 Jan 29 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1872 Dec (Box 13)
    - ----, 1873 Feb 15 (Box 13)
  - Stummer, Juda
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 2 (Box 13)
  - Swanwick, Anna, 1813-1899
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 17 (Box 13)
  - Szász, Károly, 1829-1905
    - to GE, 1879 Jul 15 (Box 13)
  - Tait, Peter Guthrie, 1831-1901
    - to GHL, 1874 Oct 29 (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Clementia (Doughty), d. 1908 (Mrs. Peter Alfred Taylor)
    - to GE, [1870?] Aug 12 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1873] Nov 9 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1878] Dec 3 (Box 13)
    - ----, [1878] Dec 8 (Box 13)
  - Teetgen, Alexander
    - to GE, 1874 Oct 22 (Box 13)
  - Temple, Frederick (Box 13)
    Judgment in the case of Craddock vs. Bray (12 July 1860) filed with letter from Charles Bray to C.H. Bracebridge, 14 July 1860.
  - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, 1st. baron, 1809-1892
    - to GHL, 1878 Aug 5 (Box 13)
  - Tennyson, Eleanor (Locker), (Mrs. Lionel Tennyson)
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 29 (Box 13)
  - Thomas, Millicent (Gilchrist)
    - to GE, 1879 Jan 5 (Box 13)
  - Tilley, Elisabeth, 1821-
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 16 (Box 13)
  - Tollemache, Marguerite Home (Purvis), (Mrs. William Augustus Tollemache), 1817-1896
    - to GE, [1878] Dec 4 (Box 13)
  - Trepplin, Charles
    - to GE, 187[5?] Jan 19 (Box 13)
  - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882
    - to GE, 1862 Jun 28
      - addressed also to GHL and filed with Trollope's letters to him, 1872 Feb 27 (Box 13)
    - to C.L. Lewes, 1880 Dec 24 (Box 13)
    - to GHL
      - Fragment, saying: I shall be at Greenwich on the 9th, n.d. (Box 13)
      - ----, 1860 Jul 9 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1860 Jul 20 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1860 Jul 23 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1860 Aug 9 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1860 Aug 14 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1861 Apr 7 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1861 Jul 3 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1862 May 15 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1863 Nov 16 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1863 Dec 13 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1864 Jan 31 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1864 Mar 21 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1864 Jun 26 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1864 Dec 24 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1865 May 30 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1865 Jun 1 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1866 Nov 9 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1868 Oct 3 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1869 Aug 13 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1869 Dec 13 (Box 13)
      - Addressed also to GE, 1872 Feb 27 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1874 May 3 (Box 13)
      - ----, 1875 Nov 1 (Box 13)
      - Accompanied by a printed map of Trollope's Barsetshire. (Box 13)
  - Trollope, Frances Eleanor (Ternan), (Mrs. Thomas Adolphus Trollope)
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 5 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1879 Dec 15 (Box 13)
  - Trübner & Co.
    - Agreement for publication of Problems of Life & Mind, addressed to GHL., 1873 May 26 (Box 13)
    - Statement on royalties due for Problems of Life & Mind, addressed to C.L. Lewes., 1880 Apr 29 (Box 13)
  - Turgenev, Ivan Sergevich, 1818-1883
    - in French, 1871 Jan 16 (Box 13)
    - to William Henry (Bullock) Hall, 1878 Oct 16 (Box 13)
  - Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    - to J.W. Cross, 1880 Dec 28 (Box 13)
      Tinker 1003
    - to GHL, 1866 Dec 1 (Box 13)
    - to Arthur Penrhyn Stanley, 1880 Dec 25 (Box 13)
      Tinker 1004
  - Tzikos, Pericles
    - to GE, 1880 Jan 1 (Box 13)
  - Verey, Joseph
    - to GE, 1859 Mar 12 (Box 13)
  - Waldstein, Charles (later Sir Charles Walston)
    - to GE, 1878 Dec 7 (Box 13)
  - Walston, Sir Charles, 1856-1927 (See: note above) (Box 13)
  - Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps), (Mrs. H.D. Ward)
    - to GE, 1873 Feb 26 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1876 Dec 1 (Box 13)
    - ----, 1877 May 27 (Box 13)